In this American English pronunciation video,
在这段美式英语发音视频中，
we're going to learn how to pronounce the OO as in BOO vowel.
我们将学习如何发音 OO，如在 BOO 中的元音。
This sound is a little different from all of the other vowel sounds.
这个音与其他所有元音音有些不同。
Other vowel sounds have one mouth position,
其他元音音有一个口腔位置，
EE for example.
例如 EE。
And it's the position of the tongue,
而是舌头的位置，
lips, and jaw that make the sound.
嘴唇和下巴形成了这个音。
For this vowel, the movement into and out of the position is just as important as the position itself.
对于这个元音，进入和离开这个位置的运动与位置本身同样重要。
OO.
OO。
We'll talk about that in a second.
我们稍后会讨论这个。
First,
首先，
let's take a look at the mouth position.
让我们看看口腔位置。
To make this sound,
要发出这个音，
the back part of the tongue stretches up towards the soft palate.
舌头的后部向软腭伸展。
The front part of the tongue remains down,
舌头的前部保持向下，
lightly touching, or just behind, the bottom front teeth.
轻轻接触或刚好在下前牙的后面。
I'm sure you can see the lips round a lot.
我相信你可以看到嘴唇圆得很多。
We want to begin this sound with lips that are more relaxed to move into this tighter lip position.
我们希望这个音开始时嘴唇更放松，然后移动到这个更紧的嘴唇位置。
Let's take the word DO as an example.
让我们以单词 DO 为例。
The lip position doesn't matter for the D sound.
对于 D 音，嘴唇的位置并不重要。
The lips can start moving into the position for the next sound when making the D,
在发 D 音时，嘴唇可以开始移动到下一个音的位置，
like in the consonant cluster, drop.
就像在辅音群中，drop。
Did you see how my lips were already forming the R when I made the D?
你看到我在发 D 音时嘴唇已经在形成 R 音了吗？
Drop.
Drop。
So what happens when we make the lip position for OO as we make the D sound?
那么当我们在发 D 音时形成 OO 的嘴唇位置会发生什么？
Do, do.
Do, do。
That's not the right sound.
那不是正确的音。
Do,
do.
do。
To make the right American OO sound,
要发出正确的美式 OO 音，
the lips have to start out, more relaxed,
嘴唇必须从更放松的状态开始，
and then come into this tight circle.
然后进入这个紧的圆圈。
This transition into position for the sound is just as important as the position itself.
这个进入音的位置的过渡与位置本身同样重要。
Let's see up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离和慢动作看看。
Lips start in a bigger flare,
嘴唇从一个更大的张开开始，
more relaxed, before moving into the tighter circle.
更放松，然后移动到更紧的圆圈。
Look at how much the corners of the lips come in for this sound.
看看嘴唇的角落在这个音中收缩了多少。
Now let's take a look at the word DO.
现在让我们看看单词 DO。
Remember,
记住，
we don't want to start with the lips in a tight circle,
我们不想从嘴唇的紧圆圈开始，
but in a more relaxed position,
而是从一个更放松的位置开始，
so they can move into the tight circle.
这样它们可以移动到紧的圆圈。
Then lips move from the flare into the tighter circle.
然后嘴唇从张开移动到更紧的圆圈。
It might help to think of this sound as OO,
把这个音想象成 OO 可能会有帮助，
starting with a more relaxed lip position.
从一个更放松的嘴唇位置开始。
OO.
OO。
In a stressed syllable,
在重读音节中，
you have an up-down shape in the voice.
你的声音有一个上升-下降的形状。
OO,
OO.
OO。
In an unstressed syllable,
在非重读音节中，
the pitch will be flatter and lower,
音调会更平和更低，
and it will be quieter and quicker.
而且会更安静和更快。
OO, OO.
OO, OO。
The OO vowel is unstressed in the word visual.
在单词 visual 中，OO 元音是非重读的。
OO.
OO。
Let's take a look up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离和慢动作看看。
Often,
通常，
unstressed vowels have a more relaxed lip position.
非重读元音有一个更放松的嘴唇位置。
Notice that, for the OO vowel,
注意，对于 OO 元音，
the lips do still come into a tight circle.
嘴唇仍然会进入一个紧的圆圈。
The OO vowel stressed.
OO 元音重读。
Do.
Do。
OO.
OO。
The OO vowel unstressed.
OO 元音非重读。
Visual.
Visual。
OO.
OO。
Example words.
例词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Blue.
Blue。
OO.
OO。
Blue.
Blue。
Issue.
Issue。
OO.
OO。
Issue.
Issue。
Suit.
Suit。
OO.
OO。
Suit.
Suit。
Move.
Move。
OO.
OO。
Move.
Move。
Influence.
Influence。
OO.
OO。
Influence.
Influence。
To.
To。
OO.
OO。
To.
To。